

# Muhammad Karbalaee

Software Developer

- muhammad.ksht@gmail.com
- Tehran, Iran



React JavaScript

Dart Flu

Flutter

Java

HTML

CSS

TypeScript

Android Development

iOS Development

NodeJS

Git



Language

English: Proficient

Acquire The Iran Language Institute's Advanced

**English Certificate** 

German: Elementary

Practiced A1



Social Network

- in muhammad-karbalae
- @muhammad-karbalaee



# Profile Summary

I'm a software developer with two years of hands-on and challenging experience in frontend development, mobile development and recently, image processing rules. The technologies that I regard myself more experienced and focused on are, React, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Flutter, native Android, but I also have foundational familiarity and a little bit of experience with, NodeJS, Spring framework, Python, OpenCV, C / C++ and native iOS with Swift.



#### Education

Bachelor in Computer Science

Institute/University: Shahid Beheshti University

Tehran, Iran

Since 2022

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

Institute/School: SAMPAD Shahid Beheshti high school

Tonekabon, Mazandaran, Iran

2017 - 2020

Advanced English Language

Institute/University: The Iran Language Institute

Tonekabon, Mazandaran, Iran

2011 - 2020



#### Work Experience

Front-End Developer

Roshan

Tehran, Iran

September 2021 - September 2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Implementing the company's new website using React
- Implementing all the API documentation websites of the company.
- Improving company's websites by SEO techniques to appear on top ten search results for relevant searches
- Fixing the bugs and adding features on one of the company's published hybrid apps using Cordova
- Practiced server-side-rendering technologies
- Complex animation design for webapps

- muhammadkarbalaee
- w muhammad-karbalaee
- Muhammad\_ksht
- muhammad\_karbalaee
- muhammad\_karbalaee
- 989373899988
- Muhammad-Karbalaee



muhammad-karbalaee-shabani

### Intern Front-End Developer

RasaHR

Tehran, Iran

May 2021 - September 2021

Tasks and Achievements

- Learning React
- Making advanced projects with React
- Getting a hint of basics of Frontend development technologies like HTML, CSS, JS

### Front-End Developer

Iran's National Elites Foundation

Tehran, Iran

December 2021 - September 2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Developing a social media productivity app with React
- Getting hands-on with legacy code on the vector open-source project
- Practicing React development with TypeScript as a better approach to tackle large-scale web applications

### Intern Mobile Application Developer

Roshan

Tehran, Iran

June 2021 - August 2021

Tasks and Achievements

- Learning the Flutter framework
- Learning the Dart programming language
- Worked NoSQL
- Implementing a podcast player mobile application from zero and alone

### Mobile Application Developer

Roshan

Tehran, Iran

Since October 2022

Tasks and Achievements

Implementing a mobile application for the company's new product

## Image Processing Programmer

Roshan

Tehran, Iran

Since September 2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Generation augmented data for company's Al projects
- Getting to know the OpenCV library

### Product Owner

Roshan

Tehran, Iran

July 2022 - October 2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Managing two groups of five intern developers working on webapps
- Guiding intern frontend developers

### Advanced Programming Teaching Assistant

Shahid Beheshti University

Tehran, Iran

February 2022 - July 2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Teaching students core Java concepts
- Teaching a separate course on native Android development with Java
- Writing testcases for assignments
- Mentoring students during the semester and for their final projects

### Freelance Programmer

Iran

November 2020 - April 2020

Tasks and Achievements

\* Accepting and Implementing C / C++ projects over the internet



#### Certificates

### Advanced English Languege

Institute: The Iran Language Institute (ILI)

August 2020

Link: drive.google.com/file/d/1ikaZvREoCuyVfysoS5eDTdO4pb7R4G5h/view?

usp=sharing

### Android Application Development

Institute: University of Science and Technology of Mazandaran

August 2021

Link : drive.google.com/file/d/1Y5hiAnu6CGHqlGHoes8gDle9NlkJNo9G/view?

sp=sharing

## 10 Days of JavaScript Challenge

Institute: Hackerrank

July 2021

Link: www.hackerrank.com/muhammad ksht?hr r=1&badge=10-days-of-

javascript&stars=5&level=3&social=linkedin

#### Version Control with Git

Institute: Quera July 2021

quera.ir/media/public/quera\_certificate/e6e2dfc168d448c492c8a5938a250fba.

pg

### JavaScript and JQuery basics course

Institute: Udemy July 2021

Link: www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-68220259-0bde-40ae-92a9

13e3e20e01ec/

### Swift Programming Language

Institute: Udemy July 2022

Link: www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d2b8a0d9-63c9-40ef-b9be-

55459f785904/



### **Projects**

Note: Many projects that I worked on can't be showcased because they are private and can't be published

--

#### Jalgorithm

November 2021

Jalgorithm, The Java library that provides all algorithms and data structures for Java developers out of the box. This is an open-source Java library that I am developing and I have gained the contribution of several people on it too.

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/jalgorithm

#### API docs

December 2021

The API documentation websites of Roshan.

Link: www.roshan-ai.ir/docs/alefba/

### Roshan websites

All the websites of the company implemented with React

Link : www.roshan-ai.ir/

#### BMI calculator mobile app

Made this app using Kotlin and native android technologies as a practice towards mobile development

Link: eithub.com/muhammadkarbalaee/BMI-calculator-app.

### Newyork Airbnb data analysis

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/newyork-airbnb-data-analysis

### Particle Systems demo website

A website showing the particle systems made with plain HTML CSS JS

Link: muhammadkarbalaee.github.io/particle-systems/

### JSON-HTML parser

A DOM and JSON parser implemented in Java

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/JSON-HTML-parser

#### Github Crawler

Github crawler implemented using web scraping techniques in Java

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/github-crawler

### Java stats

Some statistical measures and works implemented using Java with GUI

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/java-stats

### Pentago Game

The Pentago game developed as a CLI-based application using C++

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/pentago-game

#### Suffix tree demo website

Link: muhammadkarbalaee.github.io/suffix-tree/website/visualizer/

### Esmfamil game

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/esmfamil-game

## Podcast player mobile application

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/menbar-flutter

### Weather forecast mobile application

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/weather-forcast-app

### Instagram desktop application

Complete client, server Instagram clone using Java

Link: github.com/muhammadkarbalaee/instagram-desktop-application

### Multi-threaded PI calculator

Link : githuh com/muhammadkarhalaee/multi-threaded-Pi-calculator



#### Personal interests

open-source development

educational content creation

